<!--title = Preface to "Communication Systems Projects with LabVIEW"

Summary:
-->

<?xml version='1.0' standalone='yes' ?>
<LVData>
<Version>8.2</Version>


<!--OBJECTIVES------------------------------------------------------>
<String> <Name>sec</Name> <Val>Introduction</Val> </String>

<String> <Name>para</Name> <Val>
		Welcome to {term}Communication Systems Projects with LabVIEW{/term}, a multimedia-enhanced series of projects that explore
		digital communication systems through LabVIEW simulations, visualizations, and implementations of practical systems. 

		Communication systems play an exciting role in our increasingly interconnected society. Digital communication systems form the heart of 
		computer data networks, satellite communications, mobile telephones, and wireless hand-held devices. All electrical and computer engineering programs 
		emphasize communication systems as part of the core curriculum. 

		Communication systems analysis and design requires a firm grasp of mathematical models, and demands mathematical skill with signals, systems, probability, and 
		random variables. Insight and intuition, also important for the successful study of communication systems, do not always follow immediately from 
		the mathematical presentations of traditional textbooks, however. Hands-on construction of real communication systems and interactive simulations 
		that supplement the mathematics help to more quickly achieve insightful understanding of the myriad details involved in designing and optimizing a 
		communications link for a given application.

		{term}Communication Systems Projects with LabVIEW{/term} features ten laboratory projects based on the LabVIEW graphical dataflow programming environment. 
		LabVIEW offers an unparalleled way to directly translate communication system diagrams and mathematical descriptions into a LabVIEW program called 
		a {term}block diagram{/term}. The LabVIEW {term}front panel{/term} GUI (graphical user interface) that emerges automatically as part of the programming activity
		enables real-time interaction with the communication system and visualization of the signals as waveforms, binary patterns, and text. This real-time 
		interaction reveals connections, patterns, and often unexpected relationships -- the basis of strong intuition and insight. 
		Many of the projects emphasize listening to the signals as sound, further enhancing one's insight.
		
		Some of the laboratory projects simulate and visualize
		fundamental concepts such as baseband modulation, pulse shaping, intersymbol interference (ISI) and eye diagrams, while other projects result in
		fully-operational systems such as a Caller ID decoder and a text messaging system between a speaker and a microphone.

		Each project begins with an explanation of the background theory necessary to complete the project. These introductions feature 
		narrated videos called {term}screencasts{/term} that simulate a classroom lecture with a whiteboard visual aid.  Continue by constructing 
		a set of {term}subVIs{/term} (LabVIEW reusable function blocks) according to precise specifications. Each subVI includes a screencast video that demonstrates
		the LabVIEW tool in operation to introduce and explain relevant LabVIEW programming techniques for the given subVI. Once the subVIs have been 
		built and tested individually, assemble them into a working "top-level" VI (literally a {term}Virtual Instrument{/term}, the name of a LabVIEW program). 
		The project directions provide guidance through the complete development process, each step of the way.
</Val> </String>



<!--OBJECTIVES------------------------------------------------------>
<String> <Name>secend</Name> <Val></Val> </String>
<String> <Name>sec</Name> <Val>To the Instructor</Val> </String>

<String> <Name>para</Name> <Val>
		{term}Communication Systems Projects with LabVIEW{/term} has been designed to augment existing communication systems
		laboratory projects, or to serve as the complete laboratory component of an introductory engineering communication systems course. 
		
		Seven guiding principles motivate the design and organization of {term}Communication Systems Projects with LabVIEW{/term}:
</Val> </String>

<Cluster> <Name>list</Name> <NumElts>3</NumElts>
<EW> <Name>type</Name> <Choice>Bulleted</Choice> <Choice>Enumerated</Choice> <Val>1</Val> </EW>
<String> <Name>list name (optional)</Name> <Val></Val> </String>
<Array> <Name>list items</Name> <Dimsize>7</Dimsize>
	<String> <Name>String</Name> <Val>
			Build the concept for deepest learning -- transforming a set of ideas into a working system clearly demonstrates a firm grasp of the concepts
	</Val> </String>
	<String> <Name>String</Name> <Val>
			Engage the senses to develop intuition and insight -- seeing signals as waveform plots, listening to signals as sound, and changing the way
			signals are processed through virtual knobs and slider controls all work together to enhance understanding of the system under study
	</Val> </String>
	<String> <Name>String</Name> <Val>
			Interact with the system to develop understanding -- LabVIEW offers an unparalleled means to automatically generate an interactive graphical
			user interface as part of the programming activity
	</Val> </String>
	<String> <Name>String</Name> <Val>
			Motivate with "real life" activities -- many of the projects culminate in practical, working systems
	</Val> </String>
	<String> <Name>String</Name> <Val>
			Experience impairments -- once the deleterious effects of real-world constraints such as finite channel bandwidth and noise become clear
			through direct experience, the standard methods to mitigate those effects can be appreciated more deeply
	</Val> </String>
	<String> <Name>String</Name> <Val>
			Integrate teaching and instruction with project activities -- each project includes numerous narrated videos to explain concepts and to
			demonstrate task-specific LabVIEW programming techniques; each project also includes "textbook linkages" to many popular communication
			systems textbooks
	</Val> </String>
	<String> <Name>String</Name> <Val>
			Offer learning materials in a modular and open format -- each project builds on a well-defined set of building blocks; the projects can
			easily be modified, extended, and tailored to specific needs
	</Val> </String>
</Array>
</Cluster>

<String> <Name>para</Name> <Val>
		Each project requires four activities on the part of the student: (1) Study the introductory material that explains theory and concepts, (2)
		implement several subVIs as low-level building blocks, (3) assemble the subVIs into an application VI, and (4) interact with the finished VI
		to explore the theory and concepts. 
		
		Constructing the subVIs helps students to develop skills with a wide variety of LabVIEW programming
		techniques, and also helps them to establish a firm grasp on the various LabVIEW data types. The subVIs are carefully specified around 
		standard datatypes, i.e., Boolean array for bitstreams, waveform data type for "analog" signals; successful completion of the subVIs
		reduces the debugging effort required for the application VIs. Many of the subVIs are reused across multiple projects. The modularity of
		the projects -- 10 projects total with a library of over 40 subVIs -- allows the projects to be easily customized as necessary.

		An instructor's manual and complete set of application VIs and subVIs is available; please contact the author for details.
</Val> </String>



<String> <Name>secend</Name> <Val></Val> </String>

</LVData>

